Tianqi Yang

SUMMARY

Tianqi Yang is an accomplished Project Engineer and Researcher. She is a recipient of several awards, including the Dean's Scholarship from the University of Leeds, Excellent Graduation Thesis and Merit Scholarship from Tianjin University of Technology. Tianqi has a diverse range of experience, having worked as an Assistant Project Manager for Turner and Townsend and as a Project Engineer for PM Group. She has successfully delivered complex projects for high-profile clients such as Boston Scientific, Carlsberg, Nike, and AstraZeneca, with a cumulative project value exceeding 20 million pounds. As a research assistant, she employs empirical data to examine the implications of stakeholder theory on organisation design. Her work aims to contribute to the strategic management community by understanding how organisations can transition towards a broader purpose beyond profit, ultimately guiding managerial activities to address global environmental and social challenges. More information at Google Scholar and LinkedIn.

EDUCATION

University of Leeds (Pass with Merit)

09/2018 - 11/2019

Master of Science in Engineering Project Management

Leeds, United Kingdom

Tianjin University of Technology

09/2014 - 06/2018

Bachelor of Management in Construction Management

Tianjin, China

Thesis: "Transformation of Local Government Financing Firm under the Local Government Debt Governance" (Excellent Award)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

A66 Northern Trans-Pennine Highway Project Case Study

03/2024 - Now

Research Assistant

Shanghai, China/Manchester, UK

- Conduct an in-depth case study of the A66 Highway Project to empirically understand how organisations can successfully transit towards purpose orientation beyond mere profit gain.
- Study the project application document on the Planning Inspectorate and interviewing to develop a stakeholder ecosystem for the A66 Project.
- Employing New Stakeholder Theory to investigate the process of value co-creation and distribution when stakeholders are enfranchised in the collaborative relationship. Further, develop stakeholder theory and implications in organisation design.

Optimising Project Management Performance Through Digital Supply Chain Management

01/2023 - 12/2023

Shanghai, China

Research collaboration of PM Group

Explore the impact of project management optimisation in the competitive construction industry.

- Identify the main benefits of integrating digital technology into the construction project supply chain management.
- Classify the main challenges to the implementation of digital supply chain management in construction project management.
- First authored 1 conference paper, and presented the project conclusions at 11th IPMA Research Conference.

Implications of Formalised Value Management on Value Management Implementation

12/2018 - 08/2019

Master Thesis - University of Leeds

Leeds. UK

- Conducted qualitative research through in-depth interviews with 12 senior executives from diverse industries in the UK, including railway, construction consulting, and research institutes, to explore the potential benefits and challenges of formalised value management.
- Built on the theories of soft system methodology, knowledge management, and public value management, developed a set of
 actionable recommendations to enhance the effectiveness of value management practices in professional institutions
 responsible for setting industrial standards.

Transformation of Local Government Financing Firm under the Local Government Debt Governance

09/2017 - 06/2018

Bachelor Thesis – Tianjin University of Technology

Tianjin, China

- Examine the strategies employed by local governments to address and mitigate the challenges posed by mounting debt.
- Explores the development, operating risks, transformation paths, and strategies of financing firms.
- Thesis awarded with the Excellent Grade (Top 10% of students in the course).

Yang Tianqi· Curriculum Vitae

A Systematic Approach for the Design and Optimization of the Energy System of Industrial Parks

Research collaboration of China Three Gorges Corporation and PM Group.

01/2023 – 05/2024 Shanghai, China

Develop a decision-making methodology to assess the feasibility of implementing a solar PV power plant with batteries in an
industrial park. Investigated the economic and environmental impacts of the development of industrial parks with autonomous
energy systems.

Co-authored an extended abstract presented at the 1st International Conference on Carbon Neutrality.

MAIN PUBLICATIONS

- [1] Yang, T.Q, Graca Gomes, J., Optimising Project Management Performance Through Digital Supply Chain Management (2023), 11th International Project Management Association (IPMA) Conference, ISBN: 978-94-92338-39-6
- [2] Graça Gomes J., Yang T.Q., Jiang J., Towards Energy Autonomy: A Systematic Approach for Design and Optimization of the Energy System of Industrial Parks (2023), The 1st International Conference on Carbon Neutrality (ICCN-2023).
- [3] Graça Gomes J., Lin Y., Jiang J., Nie Y., Yang T.Q., Review of offshore wind project status: a new approach of floating turbines (2023) Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Power and Energy Applications, ISBN: 978-1-6654-8760-3 (4 Cit.).
- [4] Graça Gomes J., Yang T.Q., Jiang J., Lin Y., Strategic Planning for a Resilient and Sustainable Energy Future: Analysis of a 100% Renewable Energy System for Portugal in 2050 (2023) Chemical Engineering Transactions, ISBN: 979-12-81206-05-2

WORK EXPERIENCE

PM Group

Project Engineer

Shanghai, China

- Managed projects from feasibility study to handover stages, coordinating project progress, schedule, cost, safety, and risk.
- Ensured project delivery met internal revenue targets and client requirements, collaborating with discipline engineers.
- Assisted with project bidding and participated in clarification meetings for business development.
- Promoted the use of a digital platform to manage documents, contributing to the digital transformation of the China office.
- Appointed as Digitalisation Program Champion of the China office, engaging in training organised by the global digital transformation team.

Turner and Townsend 02/2020 - 09/2020

Assistant Project Manager

Beijing, China

- Conducted site visits and surveys to gather information and assess project progress and quality.
- Provided PMO (Project Management Office) service to the project team, including assisting with project planning and tracking.
- Showcased adept project management capabilities by successfully delivering projects for global industry leaders.

SKILLS

Programming and Computational Software: MATLAB, Python, MS Office, and LaTeX.

Data Processing and Visualisation: Vensim, CAD, and Revit.

Languages: Mandarin Chinese (Native), English (Full professional proficiency).

AWARDS AND HONORS

Dean's Engineering International Scholarship

2018

University of Leeds United Kingdom

(Distinction bestowed upon the top applicants for the Engineering Faculty of the University of Leeds)

Excellent Thesis Certificate 2018

Tianjin University of Technology China

(Distinction bestowed upon the top 10% bachelor thesis of the Construction Management program)

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION

Project Management Professional Certification

2021

Project Management Institute

International